const questions = [
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "A collection of books, pamphlets, etc kept in a place for reading and consultation, especially, such a collection arranged to facilitate references as by classification and indexing is called.",
        "options": [
            "Archive",
            "Library",
            "Bookstore",
            "Repository"
        ],
        "answer": "Library"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "The conventional definition of the library views the library as:",
        "options": [
            "A place for social gatherings",
            "The storehouse of knowledge",
            "A digital repository",
            "A study center"
        ],
        "answer": "The storehouse of knowledge"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Library is derived from the Latin word 'liber,' which means:",
        "options": [
            "Knowledge",
            "Book",
            "Place",
            "Collection"
        ],
        "answer": "Book"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Which of the following is traceable to the origin of the library?",
        "options": [
            "Assyria",
            "America",
            "China",
            "Egypt"
        ],
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "The first purposefully conceived and constructed library building was during the reign of:",
        "options": [
            "Alexander the Great",
            "Ptolery II Philadephus",
            "Julius Caesar",
            "Ramses II"
        ],
        "answer": "Ptolery II Philadephus"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "During the 15th Century, the invention of the printing press was by:",
        "options": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Gutenberg",
            "Galileo",
            "Newton"
        ],
        "answer": "Gutenberg"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "When and where was the collection of books in cases and the book-chaining system systematically abandoned?",
        "options": [
            "In France by 1800",
            "In Spain by 1964",
            "In England by 1700",
            "In Germany by 1900"
        ],
        "answer": "In Spain by 1964"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "The arrangement of books standing with the spine projecting outward started in:",
        "options": [
            "England",
            "France",
            "Italy",
            "Germany"
        ],
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "In what year did the University of Leiden utilize a whole floor as a library that was open to access?",
        "options": [
            "1610",
            "1650",
            "1700",
            "1550"
        ],
        "answer": "1610"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Who was credited as the first architect to design a library that conforms to modern library standards?",
        "options": [
            "Leopoldo della Santa",
            "Christopher Wren",
            "Frank Lloyd Wright",
            "I.M. Pei"
        ],
        "answer": "Leopoldo della Santa"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "The first English library act was enacted in what year?",
        "options": [
            "1800",
            "1850",
            "1900",
            "1750"
        ],
        "answer": "1800"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "What was the main catalyst of the modern library movement?",
        "options": [
            "The British Library",
            "The Library of Congress",
            "Boston Public Library of 1852",
            "The Vatican Library"
        ],
        "answer": "Boston Public Library of 1852"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a basic function of the library?",
        "options": [
            "Storage",
            "Organization",
            "Production",
            "Acquisition"
        ],
        "answer": "Production"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a criterion for the classification of libraries?",
        "options": [
            "Acquisition",
            "Collections",
            "Users",
            "Functions"
        ],
        "answer": "Acquisition"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "Which type of library serves as a depository for copyrighted publications in a country?",
        "options": [
            "Private library",
            "National library",
            "Public library",
            "Academic library"
        ],
        "answer": "National library"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Which type of library is responsible for allocating ISBN and ISSN?",
        "options": [
            "Public library",
            "National library",
            "Academic library",
            "Special library"
        ],
        "answer": "National library"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "The public library is headed by:",
        "options": [
            "Librarian",
            "Director of State Library Board",
            "Chief Archivist",
            "Head Librarian"
        ],
        "answer": "Director of State Library Board"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "The Eni Njoku Memorial Library belongs to what class of library?",
        "options": [
            "Public library",
            "Academic library",
            "Private library",
            "National library"
        ],
        "answer": "Private library"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "Which of the following is not found in a children’s library?",
        "options": [
            "Fiction",
            "Reaha",
            "Periodicals",
            "Storybook"
        ],
        "answer": "Periodicals"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "The Nnamdi Azikiwe’s Library is classified as what type of library?",
        "options": [
            "School library",
            "Public library",
            "Digital library",
            "Academic library"
        ],
        "answer": "Academic library"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "The University of Nigeria Nsukka operates a decentralized system of library. True/False?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "The collection development is made up of ……….. and ………",
        "options": [
            "Acquisition and serial section",
            "Cataloguing and reference section",
            "Circulation and bindery section",
            "Digital and audio-visual section"
        ],
        "answer": "Acquisition and serial section"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "Which of the following is not part of a serial collection?",
        "options": [
            "Newspaper",
            "Magazines",
            "Journals",
            "Textbook"
        ],
        "answer": "Textbook"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "The technical section division is made up of:",
        "options": [
            "Cataloguing section, bindery section, audio-visual section, and reprographic section",
            "Circulation section, reference section, and serial section",
            "Acquisition section, digital section, and Africana section",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Cataloguing section, bindery section, audio-visual section, and reprographic section"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "Which part of the library is referred to as the pointer to the library holdings?",
        "options": [
            "Circulation section",
            "Reference section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Serial section"
        ],
        "answer": "Cataloguing section"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "Which part of the library contains the following: Microforms, CD-Rom, Digital camera, Scanners, etc.?",
        "options": [
            "Audio-visual section",
            "Reference section",
            "Bindery section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Audio-visual section"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "Which part of the library is responsible for the repair and refurbishing of library books?",
        "options": [
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Bindery",
            "Reference section",
            "Serial section"
        ],
        "answer": "Bindery"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "The Public Service Division comprises:",
        "options": [
            "Circulation Section and Reference Section",
            "Acquisition Section and Serial Section",
            "Cataloguing Section and Bindery Section",
            "Digital Section and Audio-visual Section"
        ],
        "answer": "Circulation Section and Reference Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "Which section of the library is responsible for borrowing books to bona fide users?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Circulation section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Serial section"
        ],
        "answer": "Circulation section"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "Which part of the library answers users' queries to help them get the information they need?",
        "options": [
            "Circulation section",
            "Reference section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Bindery section"
        ],
        "answer": "Reference section"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "In which part of the library could you find books written by Chinua Achebe or books written about him?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Africana Section",
            "Serial section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Africana Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "The Digital Division is made up of:",
        "options": [
            "MTN university connect section, IT special project section, and system maintenance section",
            "Audio-visual section, reference section, and cataloguing section",
            "Circulation section, bindery section, and serial section",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "MTN university connect section, IT special project section, and system maintenance section"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "Which of the following is not part of the five laws of librarianship?",
        "options": [
            "Books are for use",
            "Every reader must read",
            "Every book its reader",
            "Save the time of the user"
        ],
        "answer": "Every reader must read"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "Which of the following attitudes does not neglect library etiquette?",
        "options": [
            "Reading several books",
            "Wearing indecent clothes",
            "Eating in the library",
            "Folding books"
        ],
        "answer": "Reading several books"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "Which part of the library operates an open access system?",
        "options": [
            "Serial section",
            "Reference section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Circulation section"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "question": "Undergraduates are allowed to borrow a maximum number of books for a maximum length of time:",
        "options": [
            "2 books for 2 weeks",
            "3 books for 3 weeks",
            "4 books for 4 weeks",
            "5 books for 5 weeks"
        ],
        "answer": "4 books for 4 weeks"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "question": "Copies of first-degree project reports written by final-year students are deposited in:",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Africana Section",
            "Serial section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Africana Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "question": "Past examination question papers of the university could be found in which section of the library?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Circulation section",
            "Serial section",
            "Cataloguing section"
        ],
        "answer": "Reference section"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "question": "The charging system used in this university library is called:",
        "options": [
            "Dewey charging system",
            "Newark charging system",
            "Library of Congress charging system",
            "Open access charging system"
        ],
        "answer": "Newark charging system"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "question": "Who defines a book as 'a non-periodical printed publication of at least 49 pages exclusive of cover pages'?",
        "options": [
            "ALA",
            "UNESCO",
            "IFLA",
            "WIPO"
        ],
        "answer": "UNESCO"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "question": "The publisher, date of publication, and place of publication make up what is called:",
        "options": [
            "Copyright",
            "Imprint",
            "Cataloguing",
            "Abstract"
        ],
        "answer": "Imprint"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "question": "Which of the following is not found at the preliminary pages of a book?",
        "options": [
            "Preface",
            "Glossary",
            "Content",
            "Foreword"
        ],
        "answer": "Glossary"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "question": "The list of technical and unusual terms with definitions is called:",
        "options": [
            "Index",
            "Glossary",
            "Abstract",
            "Bibliography"
        ],
        "answer": "Glossary"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "question": "A brief summary of the subject content of a book or periodical article is called:",
        "options": [
            "Abstract",
            "Preface",
            "Foreword",
            "Introduction"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstract"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a non-book material?",
        "options": [
            "Flash drive",
            "Projector",
            "Periodical",
            "CD-Rom"
        ],
        "answer": "Periodical"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "question": "What is the technique that enables the blind or visually impaired people to read and write?",
        "options": [
            "Braille",
            "Sign language",
            "Audio books",
            "Tactile graphics"
        ],
        "answer": "Braille"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "question": "What provides for the location of a book on the shelf?",
        "options": [
            "Accession number",
            "Call number",
            "ISBN",
            "ISSN"
        ],
        "answer": "Call number"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "question": "The type of catalogue used in the University of Nigeria Nsukka is the:",
        "options": [
            "Card Catalogue",
            "Online Catalogue",
            "Microfiche Catalogue",
            "Digital Catalogue"
        ],
        "answer": "Card Catalogue"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "question": "What describes the physical description of the book, such as the number of pages (pagination), size, volume, and illustration?",
        "options": [
            "Collation",
            "Cataloguing",
            "Classification",
            "Abstract"
        ],
        "answer": "Collation"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "question": "The serial number as stamped or written on the book by the library is called:",
        "options": [
            "Call number",
            "Accession number",
            "ISBN",
            "ISSN"
        ],
        "answer": "Accession number"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "question": "The letter-by-letter filing system is also called:",
        "options": [
            "Word by word",
            "Nothing before something",
            "Alphabetical order",
            "Numerical order"
        ],
        "answer": "Nothing before something"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "question": "The University of Nigeria Nsukka operates what type of filing system?",
        "options": [
            "Letter by letter",
            "Word by word",
            "Numerical order",
            "Chronological order"
        ],
        "answer": "Word by word"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "question": "The scheme of classification used by the University of Nigeria library is:",
        "options": [
            "Dewey Decimal Classification",
            "Library of Congress Classification Scheme (L.R.)",
            "Universal Decimal Classification",
            "Colon Classification"
        ],
        "answer": "Library of Congress Classification Scheme (L.R.)"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a constituent of call numbers?",
        "options": [
            "Class number",
            "Date",
            "Author’s number",
            "Location number"
        ],
        "answer": "Class number"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "question": "The classification scheme SF represents which department?",
        "options": [
            "Animal Science",
            "Physics",
            "Chemistry",
            "Mathematics"
        ],
        "answer": "Animal Science"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "question": "The classification scheme PA, PN, PR, PS represents which department?",
        "options": [
            "History",
            "English",
            "Philosophy",
            "Law"
        ],
        "answer": "English"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'Q' represents which faculty?",
        "options": [
            "Science",
            "Arts",
            "Social Sciences",
            "Engineering"
        ],
        "answer": "Science"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "question": "The classification scheme QD, QH, QP, RZ represents which department?",
        "options": [
            "Physics",
            "Biochemistry",
            "Mathematics",
            "Computer Science"
        ],
        "answer": "Biochemistry"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "question": "The scheme of classification 'L' represents:",
        "options": [
            "Law",
            "Education",
            "Literature",
            "Medicine"
        ],
        "answer": "Education"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'H' represents which faculty?",
        "options": [
            "Humanities",
            "Social Sciences",
            "Science",
            "Engineering"
        ],
        "answer": "Social Sciences"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "question": "Which of the following scheme of classification represents Economics?",
        "options": [
            "RD",
            "QD",
            "HB-HY",
            "K"
        ],
        "answer": "HB-HY"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'K' represents the faculty of Law. True/False?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'RD' represents a medical course. True/False?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of reference source?",
        "options": [
            "Bibliography",
            "Encyclopedias",
            "Biography",
            "Dictionary"
        ],
        "answer": "Bibliography"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "question": "Which of the following is a general encyclopedia?",
        "options": [
            "Encyclopedia of Philosophy",
            "Encyclopedia Americana",
            "Encyclopedia of Biochemistry",
            "Encyclopedia of Psychology"
        ],
        "answer": "Encyclopedia Americana"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "question": "Which of the following is a specialized dictionary?",
        "options": [
            "Thesaurus Dictionary of America",
            "Oxford Dictionary",
            "Chambers English Dictionary",
            "Webster’s New International Dictionary"
        ],
        "answer": "Thesaurus Dictionary of America"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a directory?",
        "options": [
            "World of Learning",
            "Nigeria Yellow Pages",
            "Year Book",
            "Nigerian National Telephone Directory"
        ],
        "answer": "Year Book"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a fact source?",
        "options": [
            "Almanac",
            "Year Book",
            "Handbook",
            "Thesis"
        ],
        "answer": "Thesis"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "question": "What provides information on individuals about their birthdate, education, career, and achievements?",
        "options": [
            "Encyclopedia",
            "Biography",
            "Directory",
            "Gazetteer"
        ],
        "answer": "Biography"
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "question": "Which of the following provides information about the physical and conditions of different places?",
        "options": [
            "Gazetteers",
            "Atlas",
            "Map",
            "Travel Guide"
        ],
        "answer": "Atlas"
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "question": "All except one is not a geographical source:",
        "options": [
            "Indexes",
            "Map",
            "Atlas",
            "Gazetteers"
        ],
        "answer": "Indexes"
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "question": "What is a reference source containing the author’s surname, title, page of publication, date of publication, etc.?",
        "options": [
            "Bibliography",
            "Abstract",
            "Index",
            "Glossary"
        ],
        "answer": "Bibliography"
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "question": "A form of bibliography whereby contributions to bibliography are summarized is called:",
        "options": [
            "Abstract",
            "Index",
            "Glossary",
            "Preface"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstract"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "question": "All are periodicals except one:",
        "options": [
            "Journals",
            "Newspaper",
            "Magazines",
            "Annals"
        ],
        "answer": "Annals"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "question": "Which of the following are primary sources of information?",
        "options": [
            "Journal",
            "Lecture notes",
            "Monographs",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "question": "All are secondary sources except:",
        "options": [
            "Standard",
            "Indexes",
            "Abstract",
            "Textbooks"
        ],
        "answer": "Standard"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "question": "Which of the following is a tertiary source of information?",
        "options": [
            "Encyclopedia",
            "Books",
            "Directories",
            "Library catalogue"
        ],
        "answer": "Directories"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "question": "Which of the following is not an electronic source of information?",
        "options": [
            "Journals",
            "Search engines",
            "Websites",
            "Archives"
        ],
        "answer": "Archives"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "question": "A researcher must start with what source of information?",
        "options": [
            "Primary sources",
            "Secondary and tertiary sources",
            "Electronic sources",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Secondary and tertiary sources"
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "question": "WAN means:",
        "options": [
            "Wide Area Network",
            "Wireless Area Network",
            "Web Access Network",
            "Wired Access Network"
        ],
        "answer": "Wide Area Network"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "question": "Those facts used in describing or discussing an item or a set of items are called:",
        "options": [
            "Information",
            "Data",
            "Knowledge",
            "Statistics"
        ],
        "answer": "Data"
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "question": "The technology where signals are converted from analogue to digital or vice versa is:",
        "options": [
            "Modems",
            "Routers",
            "Switches",
            "Servers"
        ],
        "answer": "Modems"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "question": "Electronic mail is also known as:",
        "options": [
            "Computer-based message system (CBMS)",
            "Internet messaging",
            "Digital mail",
            "Webmail"
        ],
        "answer": "Computer-based message system (CBMS)"
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "question": "The digital representation of a character by eight bits is called a:",
        "options": [
            "Bit",
            "Byte",
            "Nibble",
            "Word"
        ],
        "answer": "Byte"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a Boolean logic or Boolean operator?",
        "options": [
            "AS",
            "AND",
            "OR",
            "NOT"
        ],
        "answer": "AS"
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "question": "Which library is referred to as a 'library without walls'?",
        "options": [
            "Digital library",
            "Virtual library",
            "Public library",
            "National library"
        ],
        "answer": "Virtual library"
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "question": "Those resources that can be accessed via the intranet or internet are called:",
        "options": [
            "Digital resources",
            "E-resources",
            "Online resources",
            "Virtual resources"
        ],
        "answer": "E-resources"
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "question": "All except one is not a type of e-resource:",
        "options": [
            "E-book",
            "E-journal",
            "Directories",
            "Newspaper"
        ],
        "answer": "Directories"
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "question": "An organized collection of data or information that is stored in records in electronic format is called:",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Archive",
            "Repository",
            "Server"
        ],
        "answer": "Database"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "question": "Which of the following is a database for chemistry?",
        "options": [
            "Medline",
            "TEEAL",
            "SSRN",
            "PubChem"
        ],
        "answer": "PubChem"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "question": "The most common tool used to locate information on the web is called:",
        "options": [
            "Browser",
            "Search engine",
            "Database",
            "Directory"
        ],
        "answer": "Search engine"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "question": "Which of the following is a search engine?",
        "options": [
            "AltaVista",
            "Google",
            "Yahoo",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "question": "URL means:",
        "options": [
            "Uniform Resource Locator",
            "Universal Resource Locator",
            "Unified Resource Locator",
            "Unique Resource Locator"
        ],
        "answer": "Uniform Resource Locator"
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "question": "Which of the following is a referencing style common to social sciences and education?",
        "options": [
            "MLA",
            "AMA",
            "APA",
            "CSE"
        ],
        "answer": "APA"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "question": "APA means:",
        "options": [
            "American Philosophical Association",
            "American Psychological Association",
            "African Psychological Association",
            "Asian Psychological Association"
        ],
        "answer": "American Psychological Association"
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "question": "'et al' means:",
        "options": [
            "For the others",
            "And others",
            "With others",
            "Among others"
        ],
        "answer": "And others"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "question": "'Omekwe and Okafor (2009).' is what type of referencing?",
        "options": [
            "MLA",
            "APA",
            "Harvard citation style",
            "Turabian citation style"
        ],
        "answer": "APA"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "question": "Vol. 58, No 2, pp. 468-493. What is being referenced above?",
        "options": [
            "Abstract",
            "Textbook",
            "Journal",
            "Thesis"
        ],
        "answer": "Journal"
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "question": "What type of reference style is used by arts and humanities, particularly in English, literary, and cultural studies?",
        "options": [
            "MLA",
            "APA",
            "AMA",
            "CSE"
        ],
        "answer": "MLA"
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "question": "'Theory and practice. New York: Spectrum, 1995.' What type of referencing is used above?",
        "options": [
            "MLA",
            "APA",
            "AMA",
            "CSE"
        ],
        "answer": "MLA"
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "question": "What type of referencing style is used by medicine and related disciplines?",
        "options": [
            "MLA",
            "APA",
            "AMA",
            "CSE"
        ],
        "answer": "AMA"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "question": "Which section of the library should a student begin his/her search?",
        "options": [
            "Circulation",
            "Reference",
            "Serial",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Reference"
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "question": "If a researcher is looking for a journal, which section of the library should he go to?",
        "options": [
            "Circulation section",
            "Reference section",
            "Serial Section",
            "Africana section"
        ],
        "answer": "Serial Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "question": "Which part of the library is a depository of the United Nations?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Special Collections Division",
            "Serial section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Special Collections Division"
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "question": "OPAC means:",
        "options": [
            "Online Public Access Catalogue",
            "Open Public Access Catalogue",
            "Official Public Access Catalogue",
            "Organized Public Access Catalogue"
        ],
        "answer": "Online Public Access Catalogue"
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "question": "Which is a study skill?",
        "options": [
            "S3RQ",
            "RSQS",
            "SQ3R",
            "SRQ3"
        ],
        "answer": "SQ3R"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "question": "In the study skill SQ3R, the 'S' stands for:",
        "options": [
            "Study",
            "Survey",
            "Search",
            "Summarize"
        ],
        "answer": "Survey"
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "question": "We have two basic sources of law:",
        "options": [
            "Primary and secondary sources",
            "Civil and criminal sources",
            "Statutory and case law",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Primary and secondary sources"
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "question": "Those sources of law that were enacted by authoritative bodies empowered to do so by the constitution are called:",
        "options": [
            "Primary sources",
            "Secondary sources",
            "Tertiary sources",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Primary sources"
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "question": "An enactment passed by regional/state legislative, i.e., state house of assembly, is called:",
        "options": [
            "Decree",
            "Law",
            "Statutory instrument",
            "Edict"
        ],
        "answer": "Law"
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "question": "The subsidiary legislation passed by the National Assembly is called:",
        "options": [
            "Decree",
            "Law",
            "Statutory instrument",
            "Edict"
        ],
        "answer": "Statutory instrument"
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "question": "The law promulgated by the federal military government is called:",
        "options": [
            "Decree",
            "Law",
            "Statutory instrument",
            "Edict"
        ],
        "answer": "Decree"
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "question": "Which of the following is a primary source in a law library?",
        "options": [
            "Year Book",
            "Edicts",
            "Atlases",
            "Map"
        ],
        "answer": "Edicts"
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "question": "A formal written enactment of a legislative body, whether federal, state, or local government, is called:",
        "options": [
            "Treaties",
            "Statutes",
            "Precedents",
            "Decrees"
        ],
        "answer": "Statutes"
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "question": "An agreement or contract made between two or more independent nations for their mutual benefit is called:",
        "options": [
            "Treaties",
            "Statutes",
            "Precedents",
            "Decrees"
        ],
        "answer": "Treaties"
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "question": "A book aimed to provide specimens of wills, conveyances, tenancy agreements, and other forms of legal documents which legal practitioners are required to draw up for their clients is called:",
        "options": [
            "Treaties",
            "Statutes",
            "Precedents",
            "Decrees"
        ],
        "answer": "Precedents"
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "question": "The legal right a country grants an author of an original work exclusive right to its use and distribution, usually for a limited time, is called:",
        "options": [
            "Patent",
            "Copyright",
            "Trademark",
            "Intellectual property"
        ],
        "answer": "Copyright"
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "question": "The creations of the mind, such as inventions, literary and artistic works; designs; and symbols, names, and images used in commerce are called:",
        "options": [
            "Patent",
            "Copyright",
            "Trademark",
            "Intellectual property"
        ],
        "answer": "Intellectual property"
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "question": "An exclusive right granted for an invention which allows the inventor to exclude anyone else from commercially exploiting his invention for a limited period, generally 20 years, is called:",
        "options": [
            "Patent right",
            "Copyright",
            "Trademark",
            "Intellectual property"
        ],
        "answer": "Patent right"
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "question": "The sign capable of distinguishing the goods or services of one enterprise from those of other enterprises is called:",
        "options": [
            "Patent",
            "Copyright",
            "Trademark",
            "Intellectual property"
        ],
        "answer": "Trademark"
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "question": "Which of the following is eligible for copyright?",
        "options": [
            "Literary work",
            "Musical work",
            "Broadcast",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "question": "Which of the following are not permitted by the authors of their work?",
        "options": [
            "Reproduction",
            "Performance",
            "Adaptation",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "None of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "question": "Which of the following is an exception to copyright protection?",
        "options": [
            "Fair dealing",
            "Works of arts",
            "News broadcast",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "question": "When anybody who, without the license or authorization of the owner of the copyright, does an act which is controlled by copyright, it is called:",
        "options": [
            "Plagiarism",
            "Infringement",
            "Piracy",
            "Violation"
        ],
        "answer": "Infringement"
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "question": "WIPO means:",
        "options": [
            "World Intellectual Property Organization",
            "World International Property Organization",
            "Worldwide Intellectual Property Office",
            "Worldwide International Property Office"
        ],
        "answer": "World Intellectual Property Organization"
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "question": "The first multilateral treaty for the protection of literary and artistic works is commonly referred to as:",
        "options": [
            "WIPO Treaty",
            "Berne Convention",
            "TRIPS Agreement",
            "Universal Copyright Convention"
        ],
        "answer": "Berne Convention"
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "question": "Which of the following is not an agency that protects copyright?",
        "options": [
            "TRIPS",
            "UNESCO",
            "WIPO",
            "RIPO"
        ],
        "answer": "UNESCO"
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a basic function of the library?",
        "options": [
            "Storage",
            "Organization",
            "Production",
            "Preservation"
        ],
        "answer": "Production"
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a criterion for the classification of libraries?",
        "options": [
            "Acquisition",
            "Collections",
            "Users",
            "Functions"
        ],
        "answer": "Acquisition"
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "question": "Which type of library serves as a depository for copyrighted publications in a country?",
        "options": [
            "Private library",
            "National library",
            "Public library",
            "Academic library"
        ],
        "answer": "National library"
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "question": "Which type of library is responsible for allocating ISBN and ISSN?",
        "options": [
            "Public library",
            "National library",
            "Academic library",
            "Special library"
        ],
        "answer": "National library"
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "question": "The public library is headed by:",
        "options": [
            "Librarian",
            "Director of State Library Board",
            "Chief Archivist",
            "Head Librarian"
        ],
        "answer": "Director of State Library Board"
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "question": "The Eni Njoku Memorial Library belongs to what class of library?",
        "options": [
            "Public library",
            "Academic library",
            "Private library",
            "National library"
        ],
        "answer": "Private library"
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "question": "Which of the following is not found in a children’s library?",
        "options": [
            "Fiction",
            "Reaha",
            "Periodicals",
            "Storybook"
        ],
        "answer": "Periodicals"
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "question": "The Nnamdi Azikiwe’s Library is classified as what type of library?",
        "options": [
            "School library",
            "Public library",
            "Digital library",
            "Academic library"
        ],
        "answer": "Academic library"
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "question": "The University of Nigeria Nsukka operates a decentralized system of library. True/False?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "question": "The collection development is made up of ……….. and ………",
        "options": [
            "Acquisition and serial section",
            "Cataloguing and reference section",
            "Circulation and bindery section",
            "Digital and audio-visual section"
        ],
        "answer": "Acquisition and serial section"
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "question": "Which of the following is not part of a serial collection?",
        "options": [
            "Newspaper",
            "Magazines",
            "Journals",
            "Textbook"
        ],
        "answer": "Textbook"
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "question": "The technical section division is made up of:",
        "options": [
            "Cataloguing section, bindery section, audio-visual section, and reprographic section",
            "Circulation section, reference section, and serial section",
            "Acquisition section, digital section, and Africana section",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Cataloguing section, bindery section, audio-visual section, and reprographic section"
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "question": "Which part of the library is referred to as the pointer to the library holdings?",
        "options": [
            "Circulation section",
            "Reference section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Serial section"
        ],
        "answer": "Cataloguing section"
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "question": "Which part of the library contains the following: Microforms, CD-Rom, Digital camera, Scanners, etc.?",
        "options": [
            "Audio-visual section",
            "Reference section",
            "Bindery section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Audio-visual section"
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "question": "Which part of the library is responsible for the repair and refurbishing of library books?",
        "options": [
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Bindery",
            "Reference section",
            "Serial section"
        ],
        "answer": "Bindery"
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "question": "The Public Service Division comprises:",
        "options": [
            "Circulation Section and Reference Section",
            "Acquisition Section and Serial Section",
            "Cataloguing Section and Bindery Section",
            "Digital Section and Audio-visual Section"
        ],
        "answer": "Circulation Section and Reference Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "question": "Which section of the library is responsible for borrowing books to bona fide users?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Circulation section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Serial section"
        ],
        "answer": "Circulation section"
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "question": "Which part of the library answers users' queries to help them get the information they need?",
        "options": [
            "Circulation section",
            "Reference section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Bindery section"
        ],
        "answer": "Reference section"
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "question": "In which part of the library could you find books written by Chinua Achebe or books written about him?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Africana Section",
            "Serial section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Africana Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "question": "The Digital Division is made up of:",
        "options": [
            "MTN university connect section, IT special project section, and system maintenance section",
            "Audio-visual section, reference section, and cataloguing section",
            "Circulation section, bindery section, and serial section",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "MTN university connect section, IT special project section, and system maintenance section"
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "question": "Which of the following is not part of the five laws of librarianship?",
        "options": [
            "Books are for use",
            "Every reader must read",
            "Every book its reader",
            "Save the time of the user"
        ],
        "answer": "Every reader must read"
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "question": "Which of the following attitudes does not neglect library etiquette?",
        "options": [
            "Reading several books",
            "Wearing indecent clothes",
            "Eating in the library",
            "Folding books"
        ],
        "answer": "Reading several books"
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "question": "Which part of the library operates an open access system?",
        "options": [
            "Serial section",
            "Reference section",
            "Cataloguing section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Circulation section"
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "question": "Undergraduates are allowed to borrow a maximum number of books for a maximum length of time:",
        "options": [
            "2 books for 2 weeks",
            "3 books for 3 weeks",
            "4 books for 4 weeks",
            "5 books for 5 weeks"
        ],
        "answer": "4 books for 4 weeks"
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "question": "Copies of first-degree project reports written by final-year students are deposited in:",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Africana Section",
            "Serial section",
            "Circulation section"
        ],
        "answer": "Africana Section"
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "question": "Past examination question papers of the university could be found in which section of the library?",
        "options": [
            "Reference section",
            "Circulation section",
            "Serial section",
            "Cataloguing section"
        ],
        "answer": "Reference section"
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "question": "The charging system used in this university library is called:",
        "options": [
            "Dewey charging system",
            "Newark charging system",
            "Library of Congress charging system",
            "Open access charging system"
        ],
        "answer": "Newark charging system"
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "question": "Who defines a book as 'a non-periodical printed publication of at least 49 pages exclusive of cover pages'?",
        "options": [
            "ALA",
            "UNESCO",
            "IFLA",
            "WIPO"
        ],
        "answer": "UNESCO"
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "question": "The publisher, date of publication, and place of publication make up what is called:",
        "options": [
            "Copyright",
            "Imprint",
            "Cataloguing",
            "Abstract"
        ],
        "answer": "Imprint"
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "question": "Which of the following is not found at the preliminary pages of a book?",
        "options": [
            "Preface",
            "Glossary",
            "Content",
            "Foreword"
        ],
        "answer": "Glossary"
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "question": "The list of technical and unusual terms with definitions is called:",
        "options": [
            "Index",
            "Glossary",
            "Abstract",
            "Bibliography"
        ],
        "answer": "Glossary"
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "question": "A brief summary of the subject content of a book or periodical article is called:",
        "options": [
            "Abstract",
            "Preface",
            "Foreword",
            "Introduction"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstract"
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a non-book material?",
        "options": [
            "Flash drive",
            "Projector",
            "Periodical",
            "CD-Rom"
        ],
        "answer": "Periodical"
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "question": "What is the technique that enables the blind or visually impaired people to read and write?",
        "options": [
            "Braille",
            "Sign language",
            "Audio books",
            "Tactile graphics"
        ],
        "answer": "Braille"
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "question": "What provides for the location of a book on the shelf?",
        "options": [
            "Accession number",
            "Call number",
            "ISBN",
            "ISSN"
        ],
        "answer": "Call number"
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "question": "The type of catalogue used in the University of Nigeria Nsukka is the:",
        "options": [
            "Card Catalogue",
            "Online Catalogue",
            "Microfiche Catalogue",
            "Digital Catalogue"
        ],
        "answer": "Card Catalogue"
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "question": "What describes the physical description of the book, such as the number of pages (pagination), size, volume, and illustration?",
        "options": [
            "Collation",
            "Cataloguing",
            "Classification",
            "Abstract"
        ],
        "answer": "Collation"
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "question": "The serial number as stamped or written on the book by the library is called:",
        "options": [
            "Call number",
            "Accession number",
            "ISBN",
            "ISSN"
        ],
        "answer": "Accession number"
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "question": "The letter-by-letter filing system is also called:",
        "options": [
            "Word by word",
            "Nothing before something",
            "Alphabetical order",
            "Numerical order"
        ],
        "answer": "Nothing before something"
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "question": "The University of Nigeria Nsukka operates what type of filing system?",
        "options": [
            "Letter by letter",
            "Word by word",
            "Numerical order",
            "Chronological order"
        ],
        "answer": "Word by word"
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "question": "The scheme of classification used by the University of Nigeria library is:",
        "options": [
            "Dewey Decimal Classification",
            "Library of Congress Classification Scheme (L.R.)",
            "Universal Decimal Classification",
            "Colon Classification"
        ],
        "answer": "Library of Congress Classification Scheme (L.R.)"
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a constituent of call numbers?",
        "options": [
            "Class number",
            "Date",
            "Author’s number",
            "Location number"
        ],
        "answer": "Class number"
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "question": "The classification scheme SF represents which department?",
        "options": [
            "Animal Science",
            "Physics",
            "Chemistry",
            "Mathematics"
        ],
        "answer": "Animal Science"
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "question": "The classification scheme PA, PN, PR, PS represents which department?",
        "options": [
            "History",
            "English",
            "Philosophy",
            "Law"
        ],
        "answer": "English"
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'Q' represents which faculty?",
        "options": [
            "Science",
            "Arts",
            "Social Sciences",
            "Engineering"
        ],
        "answer": "Science"
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "question": "The classification scheme QD, QH, QP, RZ represents which department?",
        "options": [
            "Physics",
            "Biochemistry",
            "Mathematics",
            "Computer Science"
        ],
        "answer": "Biochemistry"
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "question": "The scheme of classification 'L' represents:",
        "options": [
            "Law",
            "Education",
            "Literature",
            "Medicine"
        ],
        "answer": "Education"
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'H' represents which faculty?",
        "options": [
            "Humanities",
            "Social Sciences",
            "Science",
            "Engineering"
        ],
        "answer": "Social Sciences"
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "question": "Which of the following scheme of classification represents Economics?",
        "options": [
            "RD",
            "QD",
            "HB-HY",
            "K"
        ],
        "answer": "HB-HY"
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'K' represents the faculty of Law. True/False?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "question": "The classification scheme 'RD' represents a medical course. True/False?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of reference source?",
        "options": [
            "Bibliography",
            "Encyclopedias",
            "Biography",
            "Dictionary"
        ],
        "answer": "Bibliography"
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "question": "Which of the following is a general encyclopedia?",
        "options": [
            "Encyclopedia of Philosophy",
            "Encyclopedia Americana",
            "Encyclopedia of Biochemistry",
            "Encyclopedia of Psychology"
        ],
        "answer": "Encyclopedia Americana"
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "question": "Which of the following is a specialized dictionary?",
        "options": [
            "Thesaurus Dictionary of America",
            "Oxford Dictionary",
            "Chambers English Dictionary",
            "Webster’s New International Dictionary"
        ],
        "answer": "Thesaurus Dictionary of America"
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a directory?",
        "options": [
            "World of Learning",
            "Nigeria Yellow Pages",
            "Year Book",
            "Nigerian National Telephone Directory"
        ],
        "answer": "Year Book"
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a fact source?",
        "options": [
            "Almanac",
            "Year Book",
            "Handbook",
            "Thesis"
        ],
        "answer": "Thesis"
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "question": "What provides information on individuals about their birthdate, education, career, and achievements?",
        "options": [
            "Encyclopedia",
            "Biography",
            "Directory",
            "Gazetteer"
        ],
        "answer": "Biography"
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "question": "Which of the following provides information about the physical and conditions of different places?",
        "options": [
            "Gazetteers",
            "Atlas",
            "Map",
            "Travel Guide"
        ],
        "answer": "Atlas"
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "question": "All except one is not a geographical source:",
        "options": [
            "Indexes",
            "Map",
            "Atlas",
            "Gazetteers"
        ],
        "answer": "Indexes"
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "question": "What is a reference source containing the author’s surname, title, page of publication, date of publication, etc.?",
        "options": [
            "Bibliography",
            "Abstract",
            "Index",
            "Glossary"
        ],
        "answer": "Bibliography"
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "question": "A form of bibliography whereby contributions to bibliography are summarized is called:",
        "options": [
            "Abstract",
            "Index",
            "Glossary",
            "Preface"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstract"
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "question": "All are periodicals except one:",
        "options": [
            "Journals",
            "Newspaper",
            "Magazines",
            "Annals"
        ],
        "answer": "Annals"
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "question": "Which of the following are primary sources of information?",
        "options": [
            "Journal",
            "Lecture notes",
            "Monographs",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "question": "All are secondary sources except:",
        "options": [
            "Standard",
            "Indexes",
            "Abstract",
            "Textbooks"
        ],
        "answer": "Standard"
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "question": "Which of the following is a tertiary source of information?",
        "options": [
            "Encyclopedia",
            "Books",
            "Directories",
            "Library catalogue"
        ],
        "answer": "Directories"
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "question": "Which of the following is not an electronic source of information?",
        "options": [
            "Journals",
            "Search engines",
            "Websites",
            "Archives"
        ],
        "answer": "Archives"
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "question": "A researcher must start with what source of information?",
        "options": [
            "Primary sources",
            "Secondary and tertiary sources",
            "Electronic sources",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Secondary and tertiary sources"
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "question": "WAN means:",
        "options": [
            "Wide Area Network",
            "Wireless Area Network",
            "Web Access Network",
            "Wired Access Network"
        ],
        "answer": "Wide Area Network"
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "question": "Those facts used in describing or discussing an item or a set of items are called:",
        "options": [
            "Information",
            "Data",
            "Knowledge",
            "Statistics"
        ],
        "answer": "Data"
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "question": "The technology where signals are converted from analogue to digital or vice versa is:",
        "options": [
            "Modems",
            "Routers",
            "Switches",
            "Servers"
        ],
        "answer": "Modems"
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "question": "Electronic mail is also known as:",
        "options": [
            "Computer-based message system (CBMS)",
            "Internet messaging",
            "Digital mail",
            "Webmail"
        ],
        "answer": "Computer-based message system (CBMS)"
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "question": "The digital representation of a character by eight bits is called a:",
        "options": [
            "Bit",
            "Byte",
            "Nibble",
            "Word"
        ],
        "answer": "Byte"
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a Boolean logic or Boolean operator?",
        "options": [
            "AS",
            "AND",
            "OR",
            "NOT"
        ],
        "answer": "AS"
    }
];